### **NAVEED AHMAD**

SHREVEPORT, LA | C: 318.848.0174 | E: DEEVAN11@GMAIL.COM

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

**Project Engineer** with experience supporting large scale projects, ensuring environmental compliance, and providing technical assistance for crews, assessing equipment and environmental impacts. Well versed in principles and methodologies of building and leading highly effective teams and supervision of technical staff.

### SKILLS

Completion Engineer | Business Management | Project Engineer | Regulatory Compliance - OSHA/EPA | Project Management | Root Cause Analysis | Record and Plot Data | Contract Negotiations | Continuous Improvement Initiatives | Hydraulic Fracturing

**Technical Skills:** Microsoft Office, Excel VBA, DrillSim5, OLGA, CMG, MATLAB, JobPilot, Petrix, FracPro, HTML, CSS, JaveScript, NodeJS, BootStrap, and JQuery

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Sam's Southern Eatery | Shreveport, LA | DEC 2019 - PRESENT PROJECT MANAGER - BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT (CONTRACT)

- Design and create cloud-based bookkeeping software for individual franchisee use to track day-to-day operational expenses and revenue and generate reports such as profit/loss statements and calculated costs (food costs, payroll, etc.).
- Assisted with beta-testing software and updates as needed, projecting to implement it across 75 locations by the end of Q3 2020.
- Update and manage corporate website including migrating new locations and review and negotiate leases and contracts for new locations.
- Coordinate with management to review terms for contracts with suppliers like Coca-Cola and US Foods and track contract requirements.
- Manage schedule of renovations, hire and train new staff, and oversee store opening logistics.
- Collaborate on-site with franchisee regarding business operations, regulations and policies and running a successful franchise.

## Basin Pump Down Service | Midland, TX | Nov 2018 - DEC 2019 PROJECT ENGINEER-COMPLETIONS

- Hired to assist in startup of Frac division including establishing SOP for field operations, training all new engineers, and conducting trainings.
- Designed completions procedures for various operators to efficiently optimize well production and reduce costs.
- Provided technical expertise during job execution, ensuring fluid, proppants, and chemicals were pumped at optimized loadings.
- Assisted with job planning and execution by monitoring and analyzing injection rates and pressures to create post job reports.

- Prepared specifications and procured materials and equipment for a timely and efficient execution of projects.
- Monitored and controlled project performance to ensure project meets agreed quality, cost and time parameters in a safe and environmentally sound manner.
- Evaluated specifications and cost estimations for preparation and submittal of project authorization for expenditure (AFEs).
- Identified risk factors and ranked the level of threat posed to project's success during technical and location-oriented risk assessments.

## FTS International | Shreveport, LA | MAY 2017 - AUG 2018 PROJECT ENGINEER-FRAC

- Analyzed and evaluated issues of job-site technical, operational, design, engineering, and geological sites and advised customer on recommended solutions to issues involving jobs being performed for the customer.
- Provided technical advice, assessments, evaluations, recommendations and counsel to customers concerning the design, development and operation of well stimulation services, processes and procedures and recommended design changes where appropriate.
- Performed real-time monitoring and evaluation of well stimulation services performed for customer.
- Monitored injection rates and pressures, performed quality control and submitted pre- and post-job assessments, evaluations, and recommendations for extensive analyses concerning treatment procedures and design processes.
- Managed multiple projects and 10 team members to ensure well design was followed per customer specifications and provided support to fracking crews in the Haynesville, Bossier, Cotton Valley, Marcellus, and Utica formations.
- Coordinated with National Operations Center (NOC) on the design, testing, results, and implementation of equipment and efficiency enhancement projects.
- Provided reports to NOC and management on field findings and made recommendations for next generation improvements.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

**Bachelor of Science in Petroleum Engineering** 

Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA

**Web Developer Bootcamp** *Udemy* 

### PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS

**Society for Petroleum Engineers** 

**American Association of Drilling Engineers**